export const calculus = [
    {
        choices: ["y is maximum", "y is minimum", "y is minimum", "x is maximum"],
        correctAnswer: "y is maximum",
        question: "At a point where y&amp;amp;#39; = 0, If y changes from positive to negative as x increases",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Minimum point", "Point of inflection", "Maximum point", "Point of intersection"],
        correctAnswer: "Point of inflection",
        question: "The point where the second derivative of a function is zero.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0 to 2pi", "0 to pi/2", "0 to pi/4", "0 to pi"],
        correctAnswer: "0 to pi/2",
        question: "The integral of sin^m (theta) cos^n (theta) d(theta) can easily be determined by using Wallis formula provided the limits are form                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["y is maximum", "x is minimum", "x is maximum", "y is minimum"],
        correctAnswer: "y is maximum",
        question: "At a point where y&amp;amp;#39; = 0, If y changes from positive to negative as x increases,",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["infinitium", "none of the above", "domain", "extrema"],
        correctAnswer: "extrema",
        question: "A collective term for maxima or minima, whether absolute of relative is called",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["median", "right", "meridian", "central"],
        correctAnswer: "meridian",
        question: "A ______ section of a surface of revolution is the section containing the axis of revolution.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["infinity/infinity", "-infinity -infinity", "infinity + infinity", "infinity, infinity"],
        correctAnswer: "infinity/infinity",
        question: "which of the following is not determinate form?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["a paraboloid", "a clssoid", "an exponential", "a sinusoid"],
        correctAnswer: "a sinusoid",
        question: "If the second derivative of the equation of a curve is equal to the negative of the equation of that same curve, the curve is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Graph ", "Set", "Formula", "Function"],
        correctAnswer: "Function",
        question: "A relation in which there is exactly one range element associated with each domain element.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["a tan(theta)", "a sec(theta)", "a sin(theta)", "a cos(theta)"],
        correctAnswer: "a sin(theta)",
        question: "The value of x in trigonometric substitution with an integrand involving (a^2 - x^2) is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Apple and pear", "Apple and banana", "Lemon and orange", "Apple and Lemon"],
        correctAnswer: "Apple and Lemon",
        question: "Newton was inspired by an apple. Pappus propositions were inspired by what fruits?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0, infinity", "0/0", "infinity^0", "infinity, infinity"],
        correctAnswer: "infinity, infinity",
        question: "Which of the following is determinate?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["zero", "positive", "infinity", "negative"],
        correctAnswer: "zero",
        question: "At the minimum point, the slope of the tangent line is                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["cosh^2x", "csch^2x", "sech^2x", "coth^2x"],
        correctAnswer: "sech^2x",
        question: "What is 1 - tanh^2x equal to?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["-csc(theta)tan(theta)", "-csc(theta)cot(theta)", "-csc^2(theta)", "sec(theta)tan(theta)"],
        correctAnswer: "-csc(theta)cot(theta)",
        question: "The derivative of csc(theta) is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["sech^2x", "sechxtanhx", "-sech^2x", "-sechxtanhx"],
        correctAnswer: "sech^2x",
        question: "If y = tanhx, find dy/dx",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["critical point", "minima", "point of inflection", "maxima"],
        correctAnswer: "critical point",
        question: "The point on the curve where the second derivative of a function is equal to zero is called",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Marrione de l&amp;amp;#39;Hospital ", "J. Bernoulli", "I. Newton", "Marquis de l&amp;amp;#39;Hospital"],
        correctAnswer: "J. Bernoulli",
        question: "The L&amp;amp;#39;Hospital rule was formulated by                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Integrating", "Differential", "Differentiation", "Differntiating"],
        correctAnswer: "Differentiation",
        question: "The operation of finding the derivative of a function.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["critical point", "minima", "maxima", "point of inflection"],
        correctAnswer: "minima",
        question: "The point of the curve where the first derivative of a function is zero and the second derivative is positive is called",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["range", "graph", "relation", "domain"],
        correctAnswer: "relation",
        question: "Any set of ordered pair is called a",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: [" cosh u + c", "coth u + c", "ln sinh u + c", "ln cos h u + c"],
        correctAnswer: "ln cos h u + c",
        question: "Evaluate the integral of tanh u du.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["catenoid", "paraboloid", "conoid", "hyperboloid"],
        correctAnswer: "paraboloid",
        question: "a solid revolution of a parabola is known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["McClaurin series", "Taylor series", "Power series", "Fourier series"],
        correctAnswer: "Power series",
        question: "An infinite series in which successive terms are of the form of constant times successive integral power of the variable, It takes the form of ao + a1x + a2x^2 + a3x^3 + ....",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["integration by substitution", "the chain rule", "integration by parts", "partial derivatives"],
        correctAnswer: "integration by substitution",
        question: "Many integrals may be evaluated by introducing a new variable of integration in place of the original variable, the two variables being connected by some suitable formulas. This process is called",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["u^a lna du/dx", "a^u lna du/dx", "a^u lnu du/dx", "u^a lnu du/dx"],
        correctAnswer: "a^u lna du/dx",
        question: "The derivative of a^u with respect to x is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["explicit function", "antiderivative", "derivative", "implicit function"],
        correctAnswer: "antiderivative",
        question: "A function F(x) is called ____ of f(x) if F&amp;amp;#39;(x) = f(x).",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["calculus variable", "limits variable", "dummy variable", "limits range"],
        correctAnswer: "dummy variable",
        question: "The variable inside the integral is called variable of integration or integration variable. It is sometimes referred to as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["derivative", "reciprocal", "product", "logarithm"],
        correctAnswer: "logarithm",
        question: "The integral of any quotient whose numerator is the difference of the denominator is the _____ of the denominator.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["John Venn", "John Napier", "John Wallis", "John Stockton"],
        correctAnswer: "John Wallis",
        question: "Who invented the symbol &amp;amp;quot;infinity&amp;amp;quot; for infinity?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Irrational function", "Rational fractional function", "Exponential logarithmic function", "Rational integral function"],
        correctAnswer: "Exponential logarithmic function",
        question: "In calculus, all functions are classified as either algebraic or transcedental. Which of the following is NOT an algebraic function?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["y = cosh x", "parabola", "y = sinhx", "x = cosh y"],
        correctAnswer: "y = cosh x",
        question: "Catenary is the shape assumed by perfectly flexible uniform cable ranging between supports. It is a graph of ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Varignon&amp;amp;#39;s theorem", "Second proposition of Pappus", "First proposition of Pappus", "Method of section"],
        correctAnswer: "First proposition of Pappus",
        question: "The area of the surface generated by rotating any plane curve about a certain axis in its plane is equal to the product of the length of the arc and the distance traveled by its centroid.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Leibniz", "Newton", "Gauss", "Newton and Leibniz"],
        correctAnswer: "Newton and Leibniz",
        question: "Calculus was invented by&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["normal", "secant", "tangent", "slope"],
        correctAnswer: "slope",
        question: "The derivative of a function is identical to the _____ of the graph of the function.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["y&amp;amp;quot; is positive", "y&amp;amp;quot; is negative", "y&amp;amp;quot; = 0", "y&amp;amp;#39; = 0"],
        correctAnswer: "y&amp;amp;quot; = 0",
        question: "At point of inflection,",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["paraboloid", "prolate", "oblate", "spheroid"],
        correctAnswer: "oblate",
        question: "When the ellipse is rotated about is shorter axis, the ellipsoid is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Critical point", "Minimum point", "Point of inflection", "Maximum point"],
        correctAnswer: "Minimum point",
        question: "The point where the first derivative of a function is zero and the second derivative is positive.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["downward", "upward", "to the left", "to the right"],
        correctAnswer: "downward",
        question: "When f&amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;#39;(x) is negative the curve of y = f(x) is concave _______.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["point of inflection", "yield point", "point of deflection", "point of intersection"],
        correctAnswer: "point of inflection",
        question: "A point at which the curve changes from concave upward to concave downward and vice versa is known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Second proposition of Pappus", "Cavalieri&amp;amp;#39;s theorem", "First proposition of Pappus", "Simpson&amp;amp;#39;s Rule"],
        correctAnswer: "Second proposition of Pappus",
        question: "The volume of any solid revolution is equal to the generating are times the circumference of the circle described by the centroid of the area. This is known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["second", "first", "fourth", "third"],
        correctAnswer: "second",
        question: "The _____ derivative of the function is the rate of change of the slope of the graph.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Point of intersection", "Minima", "Maxima", "Inflection point"],
        correctAnswer: "Inflection point",
        question: "What is the point where the second derivative is zero?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["mass moment of inertia", "location of centroid", "moment of area", "moment of inertia"],
        correctAnswer: "location of centroid",
        question: "Varignon&amp;amp;#39;s theorem is used to determine _____.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["domain", "coordinates", "range ", "ordered pair"],
        correctAnswer: "ordered pair",
        question: "Any pair of elements (x,y) having a first element x and a second element y is called",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Boolean Algebra", "Calculus", "Quantum Mechanics", "Physics"],
        correctAnswer: "Calculus",
        question: "The field of mathematics which rest on upon the fundaments concept of limits and was created by Newton and Leibniz.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["approaches infinity", "either 1 or -1", "zero or approaches infinity", "zero"],
        correctAnswer: "zero or approaches infinity",
        question: "The critical points of a graph occur when the derivative of a function is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["maximum points", "minimum and maximum", "stationary points", "minimum points"],
        correctAnswer: "minimum and maximum",
        question: "Points of derivatives which do not exists (and so equals zero) are called ____.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["f&amp;amp;quot;(a) &amp;amp;lt; 0", "f&amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;#39;(a) =/= 0", "f&amp;amp;quot;(a) &amp;amp;gt; 0", "f&amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;#39;(a) = 0"],
        correctAnswer: "f&amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;#39;(a) = 0",
        question: "At the point of inflection where x = a,",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Simpson&amp;amp;#39;s rule", "Trapezoid rule", "Chain rule", "L&amp;amp;#39;Hospital rule"],
        correctAnswer: "Chain rule",
        question: "______ is also known as the composite function rule.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["prolate", "paraboloid", "oblate", "sheroid"],
        correctAnswer: "prolate",
        question: "When the ellipse is rotated about its longer axis, the ellipsoid is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["domain", "function", "graph", "range"],
        correctAnswer: "range",
        question: "The _____ of a relation is the set of second elements of the pair in the relation.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["graph", "function", "range ", "domain"],
        correctAnswer: "domain",
        question: "The ____ of a relation is the set of first elements of pairs in the relation.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["all of the above", "y&amp;amp;quot; is negative", "the curve is concave downward", "y&amp;amp;#39; = 0"],
        correctAnswer: "all of the above",
        question: "At maximum point,",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["hyperboloid", "conoid", "catenoid", "paraboloid"],
        correctAnswer: "catenoid",
        question: "When a catenary (y = cosh x) is rotated about its axis of symmetry, it generates a solid called",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["coshx", "tanhx", "sechx", "cschx"],
        correctAnswer: "cschx",
        question: "The quantity 2/(e^x - e^-x) is equal to",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["point of inflection", "stationary point", "all of the above", "critical point"],
        correctAnswer: "critical point",
        question: "A point on the graph where the tangent line is either horizontal or vertical is known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
]